Finding Aid for Minto-Skelton Papers
William L. Clements Library, University of Michigan
- II: Walter Minto Skelton (1804-48) and Family
  - 6: Notes, Invitations, Miscellanea
    - Various notes, undated [but mainly 20th century]. Late family (?and other) notes, in various hands, made about the Minto-Skelton papers before they were given to the Clements Library.
      - 8 small pieces of light cardboard used as markers for books and manuscripts, 2 of which have notes on them (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Pieces of cloth 1845 and undated: 24 round pieces of cloth circa 4" in diameter, perhaps congratulatory or farewell remembrances to Mary McFarland (b. 1823), with writing in ink on one side and usually containing a verse or verses, a proverb, etc. (variable) and the name of the writer; frequently also a date and the home of the writer; and occasionally the name of the addressee:
      - With addressee first, then name of writer, date, and verse: (Box 5, Folder 15)
        - Mary McFarland: Saltsburgh Indiana Co. Pa. May 1845 W.H.
        - Mary: Eliza Kirkpatrick Poke Run, October 26th 1845
        - Mary: R.S. Johnston Saltzburg, September 23rd 1845
        - To Mary: Jane H. Johnston Saltzburg, October 1st 1845
        - To Mary: Saltsburgh, October the 6th 1845, S. Skelton
      - With addressee first, then name of writer and verse: (Box 5, Folder 16)
        - Mary: Mary Kirkpatrick
      - With name of writer, date, and verse: (Box 5, Folder 17)
        - May 1845 Watson Hughes (with name written backwards so as to show through correctly on the reverse)
        - Saltsburg, October 16th 1845 E.W. Robinson
        - David Kirkpatrick, October 20th 1845
        - John M. Kirkpatrick Oakland Farm, October 20th 1845
        - Joseph Skelton White Rock Eddy, October 1845
        - Rob. Skelton Freeport, 1845
        - A. Skelton, 1845
      - With name of writer and verse: (Box 5, Folder 18)
        - W.M. Skelton
        - Your Friend N[a]ncy White
        - W. N. Woodend
        - Your friend R. L.
        - Affectionately yours Jane White
        - [J.G.] McQuaide
        - Mrs. E.F. Farren Saltsburg Pa
      - With name of writer only: (Box 5, Folder 19)
        - Mrs. Mary Fretz Doylestown Pa.
        - J. Farren Saltsburg Pa.
      - 2 blank pieces of cloth (Box 5, Folder 20)
Materials housed in Print Division:
Reading card for the library of the University of Edinburgh.
Materials housed in Broadsides:
Diplomatic passport for Walter Minto, signed by Sir Horace Mann.
Certificate of Walter Minto's honorary membership in the St. Andrew's Society of New York.
Materials housed in Small Oversize:
Walter Minto's diploma from the University of Aberdeen
Princeton University Library: The Department of Rare Books and Special Collections at the Princeton University Library has letters of Minto in its miscellaneous manuscripts collection about the business of the College of New Jersey between 1787 and 1796, when Minto was a professor there, as well as two volumes of notes from his course on mathematics.
[William C. Alexander]. "Walter Minto, LL. D." The Princeton Magazine 1 (1850): 38-47.
Baskervill, P. Hamilton. The Skeltons of Paxton, Powhatan County, Virginia and Their Connections. Richmond, Virginia: Old Dominion Press, Inc., Printers, 1922. Primarily Chapter II.
Dzombak, William C. Salt in the Conemaugh Valley: The Importance of the Conemaugh Salt Works in the Early American Salt Industry (1800-1860). Saltspurg [sic], Pennsylvania: Saltsburg Historical Society, 2004.
Luther P. Eisenhart. "Walter Minto and the Earl of Buchan." Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society 94 (1950): 282-94.
John Maclean. History of the College of New Jersey from Its Origin in 1746 to the Commencement of 1854, 2 vols. Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott & Co., 1877.
Smith, Robert Walter. History of Armstrong County, Pennsylvania. Chicago: Waterman, Watkins, 1883. Primarily Chapter XX.
Joseph D. Zund. "Minto, Walter." Dictionary of American Biography Online. American Council of Learned Societies, February 2000. The most recent biography.
Minto papers - Correspondence addressed to Walter Minto (unless noted), by correspondent:
Addison, Alex. (5 letters)
11 September [1786], Philadelphia
23 October 1786, Washington [Pa.]
7 January 1787, Washington [Pa.]
20 July 1787, Washington [Pa.]
23 April 1795, Washington [Pa.]
Addison, Jean. (1 letter)
23 October 1786 (with P.S. from husband, Alex. Addison [see preceding], dated 26 October), Washington [Pa.]
Aitchison, Alex., Jr. (9 letters)
6 April 1774, Edinburgh
7 December 1774, Edinburgh
8 February 1775, Edinburgh
15 February 1775, [Edinburgh]
18 February 1775, [Edinburgh]
8 March 1775, Edinburgh
15 March 1777, Edinburgh
19 July 1787, Edinburgh
27 June 1788, Edinburgh
Anderson, Jo. (1 letter)
20 April 1775, Lonend [Paisley, Renfrewshire]
Anderson, Thomas. (2 letters)
11 December 1774, Selkirk
10 January 1789, Selkirk
Anonymous (1)–to Walter Minto c/o Mr. Chrystie, New York. (1 letter)
9 September 1787, Philadelphia (mentions "Aunt ana Elisa")
Anonymous (2) (1 letter)
20 February 1788, New York (probably from a woman; mentions Mr. Chrystie, Mr. and Mrs. Tad, Miss Graff, Miss Robisson)
Anonymous (3): "Mr[?s]. laconic"–to Walter Minto, New York. (1 letter)
Undated [?1788-89] (sounds as though she may be an intermediary for letters that will bring him happiness, perhaps in his courtship of Mary Skelton)
Anonymous (4)–to Walter Minto at no address. (1 letter)
Undated [1788-96] (brief note of thanks, probably with a little money enclosed, for Minto's attention to his/her son)
Anonymous (5) [= M. Chrystie: same hand as M. Chrystie letter below and M. Chrystie letters in Series 2.I; refers to "Mr. Chrystie" as though he is her husband]. (1 letter)
1 March 1789, New York (mentions letter from Mr. Hutchison to Walter Minto; also mentions Mrs. Tad, Miss Ga[u])
Anonymous (6) "A friend to Learning". (1 letter)
20 August 1792, New York (your college, where my son is, has done injury by recommending "a Silly, Ignorant Boy, to be a Professor of Languages," but you could make up for it by conferring an L.L.D. on Mr. Peter Wilson of Flatbush)
Anonymous (7-8) (1 (?) letter)
No date, no address (2 leaves; probably 2 separate items, as hands are not the same; cannot make out much of either: 1st appears to begin "Sir"; mentions "Miss Grant," "Mrs. Rit," "his friend M P," "Minto"; 2nd has a seal on the back and mentions "Johnson's")
Barlass, William. (1 letter)
22 March 1776, Paisley
Baynton, Peter. (1 letter)
6 July 1789, Philadelphia (requests Minto to appear on the commission for examining witnesses produced by John Morgan in his suit against the executors of John Baynton) (formerly in 1934 Minto donation)
Bell, John. (1 letter)
13 June 1774, Glasgow (mentions what must have been a serious illness of Minto)
Betts, H. (1 letter)
12 January 1780, Leghorn
Blackhall, John, Reverend. (4 letters)
14 October [1782], Berwick
6 February 1783, Berwick
19 May 1783, Berwick
3 April 1786, Berwick
Bond, P[hineas]. (1 letter)
20 June 1787, Philadelphia
Bonrie, Ralph. (1 letter)
27 September 1792, Philadelphia (mentions "the Son of Monsieur Woofoin" now under Minto's care)
Broom, Jacob (signer of the U. S. Constitution) (2 letters)
30 July 1794, Wilmington
12 September 1794, Wilmington
Brown, Colin (to W.M. c/o Major Chrystie, New York) (1 letter)
14 August 1787, Philadelphia
Buchan, Lord (= David Steuart Erskine, 1742-1829; noted Scottish antiquarian) (17 letters)
30 July 1784, Kirkhill
26 May 1785, Kirkhill
23 August 1785, Kirkhill
22 September 1785, Kirkhill
25 November 1785, N. Edinburgh
8 January 1786, Great Pulteney Street
16 January 1786, London
23 January 1786, London
10 February [1786], [prob. Edinburgh or Kirkhill; not London]
[May 1786; received 12 May]
23 September 1786, Kirkhill
December 1786, Edinburgh
16 February 1789, Edinburgh
27 March 1790, Dryburgh Abbey
28 June 1791, Dryburgh Abbey
5 August 1793, Dryburgh Abbey
9 September 1794, Dryburgh Abbey
Buchan, Lord, to Joseph Reed, Philadelphia. (1 letter)
13 May 1786, Kirkhill (letter of introduction for Walter Minto, who probably took it with him to America; cf. Eisenhart)
Buist, John. (6 letters)
16 May 1786, Greenock
16 August 1791, Greenock
13 March 1793, Greenock
13 August 1794, Greenock
24 March 1795 (with P.S. dated 27 March), Greenock
6 August 1795, Greenock
C., J. (1 letter)
5 March [1786], Stirling
Chalmers, Robert. (1 letter)
3 August 1774, Pathead
Chrystie, M., to Mrs. Clark--to be left at Dr. Minto's. (1 letter)
29 October [1790's–may be near end of Walter Minto's life, since it mentions his illness/ague] (talks about Minto's health, refers to Mrs. Minto; give love to Mr. Clark, also our "young friend Polly" and sister Betsey)
[Chrystie, M.].
(see Anonymous (5) above)
Collins, Isaac. (2 letters)
15 December 1788, Trenton (about proofs of Minto's inaugural oration at College of New Jersey)
13 November 1792, Trenton (gives estimate for printing Minto's calculations)
Coventry, Andrew. (2 letters)
29 December 1785, Stichill
24 September 1794, Edinburgh
Drummond, Catherine (1762-1833; daughter of John Drummond, 3rd Laird of Logie Almond, Perthshire) (59 letters, numbered #1 to #48 (with #32 and #33 chronologically reversed, #35 and #46 omitted), plus 1 undated letter preceding #1, 6 dated letters following #48, and unnumbered letters between #25 and #26, #38 and #39, #42 and #43; all letters signed "CD" or unsigned unless noted; for "Catherine" see Minto's letter to Drummond in section B below)
Tuesday morning [March 1784 on outside by WM], St. John's Street [Edinburgh] (handwritten invitation from "Miss Drummond," with numbers on inside pages in Walter Minto's hand)
(1) 24 [June 1784; Recd. 26 June 1784], Logie Almond
(2) [July 1784; 14 July on outside by WM], Logie Almond
(3) 22 July 1784, Logie Almond
(4) [July/August 1784] (partly in French)
(5) 19 August [1784], Logie Almond
(6) [Recd. 21 August 1784]
(7) 6 September 1784
(8) 4 October [1784]
(9) 10 November [1784] (with P.S. dated 22 November), Stobhall (signed "CDrummond")
(10) 25 November 1784, Logie Almond
(11) [November/December 1784] (has names of her siblings on outside in Minto's hand: Will., Thom., Cath., Eliz., Maria, Louisa, Fanny)
(12) 13 December 1784
(13) 3 January 1785, Logie Almond
(14) 11 January 1785, Logie Almond
(15) 21 January [1785]
(16) 6 February 1785
(17) [February-April 1785]
(18) [February-April 1785]
(19) [February-April 1785]
(20) [February-April 1785]
(21) [February-April 1785]
(22) 2 May 1785, Logie Almond
(23) [May 1785] (with P.P.S. dated 25 May and 26 May)
(24) 26 June 1785, Logie Almond
(25) 28 June [1785], [stamped Perth]
Thursday [21 July 1785 added inside by WM], St. John's Street [Edinburgh] (this and the next three, all in French, are sewn together and have their pages numbered 4-7)
[22 July 1785 added inside by WM]
[24 July 1785 added inside by WM]
[29 July 1785, plus Vendredi, added inside by WM]
(26) 8 August [1785], [stamped Perth] (mentions Uncle William and Mrs. Murray; also Lord Dunmore)
(27) [Recd. 1 September 1785]
(28) 4 September 1785
(29) [Recd. 16 September 1785] (in French)
(30) [Recd. 5 October 1785] (in French)
(31) [Recd. 10 October 1785] [stamped Perth] (in French)
(33) 11 October 1785 (in French)
(32) 31 October [1785] [stamped Perth] (in French)
(34) [November 1785-January 1786] (has note: "La 35eme fut brulee")
(36) [November 1785-January 1786] (in French)
(37) [Recd. 8 February 1786]
(38) [Recd. 16 February 1786] (in French)
Mardi [21 March 1786 added inside by WM] (in French)
(39) [3 April 1786 added inside by WM] (in French)
(40) [8 April 1786 added inside by WM] (in French)
(41) Jeudi [April/May 1786] (in French)
(42) 11 May [1786 added inside by WM] (in French)
[19 May 1786 added inside by WM] (in French)
(43) 2 June [1786], Edinburgh (in French)
(44) 2 February 1787 (sent to Philadelphia; recd. 21 July)
(45) 17 April 1787, Logie Almond (in French) (sent to Philadelphia; recd. 30 November)
(47) 28 January 1788 (in French) (all from here on sent to Princeton; recd. 23 April)
(48) 5 July [1788] (the day and month are from a P.S.; in French, English, and Italian; rejects Minto's proposal in his letter to her in section B below)
16 January 1789, St. John's Street [Edinburgh] (in French) (recd. 11 May; replied to this one and the next two on 5 January 1790, according to a note on the outside of each)
29 March 1789 (in French)
25 October 1789, George Street [Edinburgh]
24 February 1790, George Street [Edinburgh] (mentions his letter of 5 January telling her of his marriage)
19 July 1790, Logie Almond
27 April 1791, [stamped Perth] (mostly in English, a bit in French)
Erskine, David Steuart.
(see Buchan)
Fisher, Miers. (1 letter)
18 March 1789, Philadelphia
F[ord], M[artha] ("Mrs. Forbes" on outside of letter, also on the following letter, in what appears to be Minto's hand) (1 letter)
12 September 1778, Kensington Gore (mentions WM's and Johnny's illnesses; was also anxious about George, but was reassured by the latter's letter to her)
F[ord], M[artha], to George and John [Johnstone] (sons of George) (1 letter)
26 August 1778 (signed "Mother"), Kensington Gore (no address on outside; probably enclosed in the preceding, since it has the same folds; mainly about their father's actions vis-a-vis the French fleets off Sandy Hook)
Gale, R.H. (1 letter)
6 April 1792, Baltimore
Garrick, D[avid], to Governor Johnstone. (1 letter)
28 June 1772, Hampton
Grant, John (for Minto at Colonel Gurney, Philadelphia, also at Mr. Christie, New York) (1 letter)
18 December 1786, "Ma[nre] of Roha[t]in near Keith Banffshire No. Brid.'"
Gurney, Francis. (4 letters)
29 January 1787, Philadelphia
18 February 1787, Philadelphia
28 March 1787, Philadelphia
25 June 1787, Philadelphia
Harpur, Robert. (1 letter)
28 February 1787, New York (about Erasmus Hall)
Hubey, Nicholas. (1 letter)
3 May 1792, Baltimore
Hunter, Andrew (Professor of Mathematics and Astronomy at College of New Jersey in 1804) (1 letter)
10 June 1794, Woodbury [N.J.]
Hutchinson, James, and John Vaughan (secretaries of American Philosophical Society) (1 letter)
6 February 1789, Philadelphia (informing Minto of his election to APS)
Imlay, [James H.]. (1 letter)
3 December 1795, Allentoun [Pa.]
Irving, Thomas. (1 letter)
14 December 1789, Somerset County Maryland
Jamieson, John (much published religious scholar) (7 letters)
25 October 1785, Forfar
16 November 1785, Forfar
24 December 1785, Forfar
[3-23 February 1786]
10 October 1787, Forfar
15 August 1792, Forfar
1 February 1794, Forfar
Johnstone, B[arbara], [Lady] (mother of George), to John Johnstone (brother of George), Wasterhall. (1 letter)
2[-] December 1764
Johnstone, George. (3 letters)
30 May 1776, London (instructions to Minto about his sons and thoughts on education, discipline, etc.)
30 May [1776], Erith (a kind of P.S. to the preceding letter)
30 October 1778, London (copy in WM's hand) (see below section B, Johnstone, item a)
Kemp, John. (2 letters)
5 March 1791, New York
26 September 1796, New York (introducing a Mr. Geary from Scotland, who has charge of the Academy at Trenton)
Laurie, Joseph. (1 letter)
3 March 1795, Princeton
Lawson, George. (2 letters)
18 March 1786 (has a P.S. by Lawson's wife Margaret), Selkirk
March 1787, Selkirk (sent to Washington College, Annapolis; then forwarded to New York c/o Dr. Mason)
Littlejohn, Thomas B. (1 letter)
22 October 1794 New York
Livingston, [?B.] H. (1 letter)
28 February 1787, New York–addressed to Dr. Walter Minturn (Erasmus Hall school opens in May, and Minto is their prime candidate for principal; invites Minto to New York for a visit and interview)
Marth, John. (1 letter)
2 March 1779, Malaga
Mason, John. (2 letters)
4 March 1787, New York (about Erasmus Hall, accompanying letter from Rev. Dr. Livingston above)
5 March 1791, New York
McCormick, Daniel, to George Morgan Esq. (1 letter)
1 November 1794, New York
McDonald, Jo. (fellow Scottish immigrant and Presbyterian minister) (10 letters)
21 September 1783, Berwick
28 June 1784, Greenock
19 August 1786, Albany–addressed to Minto c/o Dr. Benj[torn], Philadelphia
11 July 1787, Albany
29 June 1789, Albany
10 November 1789, Albany
11 November 1791, New Brunswick
28 May 1792, New Brunswick
2 November 1792, Albany
12 July 1794, Albany
Minto, Agnes (sister of Walter Minto) (1 letter)
1 March 1774 [in spite of fact that 1779 is on the outside], Edinburgh (mentions Minto's recent illness)
Minto, David (brother of Walter Minto) (1 letter)
10 April 1787, place cut out
Minto, M[ary] [Skelton] (wife of Walter Minto) (1 letter)
7 October [probably 1789, though could be later; note that it sounds as though early in their marriage and this, from Minto's letter to Anon. dated 1[2] July 1789: "As soon as our vacation begins, an event is to take place of the greatest importance to my future happiness. Immediately after this I am under engagements which I cannot dispense with to go to N. York."]-- addressed to Minto at Col. Chrysties Maiden Lane No. 17 New York
Minto, Nanny (sister of Walter Minto) (5 letters)
18 August 1786, Edinburgh–addressed to Minto c/o "Dr. R[u]sh, Philadelphia"
10 June 1788, Edinburgh
26 February 1789, Edinburgh
20 September 1794, Edinburgh
5 May 1795, Edinburgh
Minto, Nanny, to Mrs. Col. Christie. (1 letter)
14 February 1797 (has received her sad account of Walter's death and mentions the "embarrassment of Mrs. Minto's affairs" [presumably financial]; in a P.S. dated 10 March 1797 says she has received a box with a parcel of newspapers and a few articles of her brother's, but not one line from Mrs. Minto)
Minto, Robert (uncle of Walter Minto), to Walter Minto Sr. (3 letters)
19 July 1775, Jamaica
30 January 1779, Liverpool
4 January 1783, London
Minto, Thomas (brother of Walter Minto) (12 letters)
(1st 5 letters numbered #15-#19, 7th numbered #20):
23 August 1785, Crosbie, Cumberland
13 September 1785, Liverpool
29 September 1785, Liverpool
14 November 1785, Liverpool
6 February 1786, Kingston [Jamaica]
22 March 1787, Hanover, Jamaica
24 April 1787, Hanover, Jamaica
10 September 1787, Hanover, Jamaica
12 June 1789, Hanover, Jamaica
25 June 1791, Hanover, Jamaica
30 July 1791, Hanover, Jamaica
5 September 1796, Hanover, Jamaica (says their brother David died on 19 August 1796, and he is uneasy about Walter's health)
Minto, Thomas, to his sister Nanny Minto. (2 letters)
10 February 1781, St. James, Jamaica
24 July 1781, St. James, Jamaica
Minto, Thomas, to his parents, Walter Minto Sr. and Agnes Waugh. (7 letters)
Undated [but perhaps Spring 1777, from Jamaica] ("I wrote to you from Kingston," says it has been over 3 months since he came to this country, and talks about a Negro rebellion begun by a boy "belonging to a Dr. Spence parish of Hanover next parish to St. James")
26 July 1777, St. James, Jamaica (with P.S. to his sister Nanny)
10 April 1778, St. James, Jamaica (includes a letter for his sister Nanny Minto beginning on page 3)
1 August 1778, St. James, Jamaica
21 May 1780, St. James, Jamaica
10 February 1781, St. James, Jamaica (with P.S. dated 15 February)
24 July 1781, St. James, Jamaica
Minto, Walter, Sr. (9 letters: a few signed by Walter Minto Sr.'s wife and/or children)
Undated [between 2 November 1773 and 11 March 1775, when he was staying in East Rhynd; "176odd" on outside of letter]
29 August 1777 (parents are very worried about Walter Jr.'s brother Thomas and uncle Robert in Jamaica; have not heard from them)
9 February 1778
2 June 1779, Edinburgh
14 June 1780, Edinburgh
2 August 1780, Edinburgh (includes a P.S. from A. Waugh to
22 January 1781, Edinburgh
12 September 1782, Edinburgh--no destination, but to somewhere overseas: perhaps Ostend, since it mentions Minto coming home via there
11 April 1787, Edinburgh
Minto, Walter, Sr., to Revd. Buist (see above) (1 letter)
18 January 1790, Edinburgh
Minto, Walter, Sr., to Mary Minto. (1 letter)
15 February 1798 (addressed "Dear Daughter"; says he can't give her any advice about selling the farm; mentions his daughter's death on 3 September 1797; spends most of his letter laying out his financial trouble and asking Mary Minto to send him something)
Mundell, John. (1 letter)
28 April 1789, Fredericksburg Virginia
N[?ichol]nson, William. (2 letters)
23 May 1786, Edinburgh
19 June 1789, Edinburgh (mentions "our friend Chrystie," Mr. Bowre/Bowie/Bonrie, etc.)
O., [A.]. (1 letter)
13 March 1786 (mentions Minto's degree, asks the name of the ship he sails on for America "in the middel of April" and when he leaves Edinburgh)
Oliver, Katharine (cousin of Minto) (1 letter)
30 November 1775, Inverleithen
Oliver, Stephen. (1 letter)
11 September 1794, Marton (letter of recommendation for James Somerveil)
Panton, Thomas. (1 letter)
7 November 1778, Leghorn
Paterson, Samuel. (3 letters)
22 May 1788, Edinburgh
15 September 1789, Edinburgh
21 June 1792, Edinburgh (says he received a package from Minto's father and knows to whom it should go [=Charlotte Drummond])
Ragueneau, Abraham. (1 letter)
9 September 1776, Leghorn
"Rhomboidus," Timothy. (1 letter)
"Paulus Mart. 5722" [1786, between February and May] ("Dear Mr. Domine Squire Doctor Mintot": joking letter with mathematical and astronomical references congratulating Minto on his doctorate from "University of St. Andrews")
Rittenhouse, David (1732-96; noted astronomer and clockmaker) (6 letters)
10 March 1790, Philadelphia
15 November 1790, Philadelphia
26 September 1791, Philadelphia
25 May 1792, Philadelphia
4 April 1793, Philadelphia
28 October 1795, Philadelphia
Rittenhouse, David, to Mary Minto. (1 letter)
21 December 1795, Philadelphia (mentions Minto's severe illness)
Rochefontaine, Stephen. (2 letters)
9 October 1793, Princeton
14 February 1795, Philadelphia
Rodgers, John (noted clergyman, Revolutionary War chaplain) (1 letter)
16 May 1795, New York (about his funeral oration for Witherspoon)
Rush, Benjamin (signer of the Declaration of Independence) (5 letters)
5 January 1789, Philadelphia (thanks Minto for a copy of his speech; contains a recipe in French inside, in neither Rush's nor Minto's hand)
24 March 1792, Philadelphia (wishes to send his son John to the College and requests Minto to take him into his family)
30 April 1792, Philadelphia (same subject)
9 May 1792, Philadelphia (same subject)
19 September 1792, Philadelphia (his son's disgrace, has decided to take him home; immoral life at the College)
Skelton, Joseph, to Mary [Skelton] Minto. (1 letter)
16 March 1797, New York (addressed "Dear Aunt," but from date this should be her brother, not a nephew; he had her letter from Toney; mentions details of the auction of someone's goods, probably her husband's, and urges her not to sell the farm for a while)
Skinner, Abraham. (1 letter)
Undated [1790s] (mentions Princeton)
Slop, Giuseppe A[ntonio] (1740-1808; noted Italian astronomer, professor at Pisa) (3 letters)
[1778, early December: before the 10th; sent to Livorno] (numbered #10) (in Italian)
[Recd. 10 September 1785] (numbered #22; with P.S. by his son, Francesco) (in Italian), Pisa
10 February 1786 (numbered #23) (in French and Italian), Pisa
Slop, Giuseppe, to Governor Johnstone. (1 letter)
13 November 1778, Pisa (in French) (see below, section B, Johnstone, item a)
Smith, B. (1 letter)
14 November 1795, Trenton (has to do with a signature for a deed in Philadelphia)
Smith, Samuel [Stanhope] (President of College of New Jersey, 1795-1812) (1 letter)
Saturday 1 p.m. [15 November 1794 inside, perhaps by Minto], Tusculum [near Princeton] (mentions John Witherspoon dying half an hour earlier)
Snowden, Isaac, Jr., to Mary Minto. (1 letter)
1 July 1797, Philadelphia (about Walter Minto's tombstone, whether it should be in Latin or English)
Steuart, Selkirk. (2 letters)
20 May 1786, Bunker's Hill
24 July 1792, Edinburgh
Stockton, R[ichar]d (son of signer of the Declaration of Independence) (1 letter)